A Finding Aid to the LeRoy Neiman Papers, 1938-2005, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Artifacts and Artwork, 1953-2002, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 69-76, 84; 4.8 linear feet)
  - Neiman's Restaurant and Lounge paraphernalia, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 11)
    (menus, napkins, drink stirrers and a matchbook from this restaurant in California, which uses Mr. Neiman's name and displays his serigraphs, but was created without his knowledge or participation, as there is no copyright on his name or image)
  - Nametags and IDs, Archival Resource Key (Box 69)
    - Leather Wallet (containing badge naming Neiman as an Honorary Deputy Constable of the City of Las Vegas), circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Vinyl Card Wallet (with cards), 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - American Sportscasters Association Hall of Fame Awards Dinner, 1984-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 14)
    (souvenir canister from third annual dinner, bears reproduction of LeRoy Neiman drawing on lid)
  - Chef John Bennett T-shirt with Neiman Silkscreen, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Classic Moments Watches, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 16)
    (tray of changeable watch faces bearing miniature reproductions of Neiman paintings)
  - Denver Grand Prix, Lucite Plaque with Reproduction of Denver Grand Prix, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 17)
  - Playboy Electronic Datebook, 1993; Archival Resource Key; (three 3 ½ inch floppy disks with user's manual and box) (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - "LeRoy Neiman/The Impressionist Collection" Note Cards, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - Frank Sinatra Duets and Duets II Album Covers, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key; (two CDs in jewel cases with inserts) (Box 69, Folder 20)
  - Miniature Replica World Boxing Association Championship Belt, 1996; Archival Resource Key; (engraved with LeRoy Neiman's name, 'bejeweled' leather and metal with faux sheepskin backing and Velcro closure) (Box 69, Folder 21)
  - The Art of Playboy CDROM, 1997; Archival Resource Key; (in box, still in plastic wrapping) (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Panorama, Jim Hall CD, with Neiman Cover Art, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Awards, Key to the City of Las Vegas, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - 123rd Kentucky Derby and Derby Day Paddock Decorative Picture Frame, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Playboy's LeRoy Neiman Selection Cigars by Don Diego, 1997; Archival Resource Key; (mock up cardboard cigar box and wooden cigar box) (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Rhythm & Smoke: The Cuba Sessions, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key; (2 CD's with English and Spanish covers) (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Folies Bergere LeRoy Neiman Chips, 1999; Archival Resource Key; (2 chips bearing LeRoy Neiman images in a black presentation box, Duvall-LeRoy Elegance de Champagne Cuvee LeRoy Neiman; 2 one-bottle boxes; one metal cork cap) (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - 82nd PGA Championship at Valhalla, 2000; Archival Resource Key; (service ID badge with metal clip and neck strap) (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Frank Sinatra "Classic Duets" Album Cover 2002 - CD still in plastic wrapped jewel case, Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Hats, Archival Resource Key (Box 71)
    - One paint-covered off-white newsboy cap, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - One blue chef's cap with "LeRoy" signature embroidered in red on one side, heart emblem on other side, Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Femlin 1953-2005 - one cap with Femlin character on front and Femlin brand label and LeRoy Neiman signature embroidered on back, Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - 1984 Olympics, Los Angeles - one 1984 Olympics painter's cap, with a message to LeRoy Neiman from the mayor written in pen on side of cap, Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Dodgers Centennial, 1990 - one Dodgers Centennial cap, Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Playboy's LeRoy Neiman Selection Cigars by Don Diego, - one Playboy Cigars by Don Diego cap, denim with suede bill, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Shoes, Archival Resource Key (Box 71)
    - Three single sneakers, paint covered, two signed and dated by Neiman, Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - One pair of leather moccasins, Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Large Artifacts, Archival Resource Key (Box 72)
    - Tray with reproduction of painting of a Boston Red Sox player (Ted Williams?) swinging a bat; this is a template of a product which was never produced, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - The Heavyweights vinyl LP with album art by Neiman, 1970, still in original plastic wrapper 1984 Olympics, Los Angeles - A plaque from the Japanese magazine "Shukan T.V. Guide," thanking Neiman for his help on their Olympics edition magazine cover, which shows a painting of an Olympic runner., Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Sign promoting the release of The Golden Bear, 1992 serigraph of Jack Nicklaus, Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Celebration 2000 - Plaque given to LeRoy Neiman by Centaur Galleries on the occasion of his Celebration 2000 exhibition, naming him "Artist of the Decades", Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Photographs - Framed photograph of LeRoy Neiman and Charles Barkley unveiling portrait of the basketball player on the occasion of his retirement, 2001 - back of frame has LeRoy Neiman's handwritten note describing the photo, Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Two empty sample boxes for jigsaw puzzles of the 1983 painting, Elephant Family, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 73)
  - Bags, Archival Resource Key (Box 74)
    - London Playboy Club shoulder bag, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Steve Garvey Sports Classic tote bag, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Larry Bird, 1993 - Larry Bird Night duffel bag, Archival Resource Key (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Clothing, Archival Resource Key (Box 75)
    - Yellow Nomex suit with Lynn Quayle's name embroidered on breast, Archival Resource Key (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - White satin bomber jacket with "LeRoy" embroidered on breast and stunt person agency logo on back, Archival Resource Key (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Silk men's shirt printed with a collage of Neiman works in sepia tones, Archival Resource Key (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Femlin T-shirt, 1953-2005, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key; (3 brand label t-shirts) (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Hambletonian Harness Race Painting, 1995; Archival Resource Key; (t-shirt with Hambletonian name and reproduction of painting on front) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - 2 T-shirts from the "Fringe TOMAR 2000" Festival Internacional de Danca Contemporanea, LeRoy Neiman image reproduced on front or back of shirt, Archival Resource Key (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Paint Clothes, Archival Resource Key; (6 pairs pants, 2 jumpsuits, 1 shirt) (Box 76)
  - Oversized Drawings and Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 84)